We are going to be creating a secondary zone in this video.
So, a secondary zone is a really only copy of the primary zone that is stored on a different
server.
The secondary zone cannot possess updates and can only retrieve updates from the primary
zone.
And the secondary zone facilitate for tolerance and load balancing features by means of storing
additional copies of the primary zone.
So, what we are going to be doing right now is we are going to be creating a secondary
standard zone.
So, what we need to do right now is to just right click the phone, look of the zone and
then click new zone.
So, at this moment we are going to be selecting another new zone with our logistic nest.
And then here we are going to be selecting the secondary zone.
So, for a secondary zone, you can see that this stored in active directory was unchecked
and cleared.
So, it means secondary zone cannot be stored in active directory.
So, they just click next.
And now we need to enter the zone name.
So, the zone name is going to be the following.
I am going to enter the little bit of curl, S, D, then zone 1.
And then this is going to be our secondary zone name.
So, curl, you can see that the word have it there, the primary zone, and then they just
click next.
So now we want to enter the IP address of our secondary cell, of our primary server where
the zone will be transferred from.
So, let's enter it's going to be 192.168.111.154.
So, if I enter, you can see that this is 0, 1, and then just click next.
And then let's click finish.
So, by clicking finish, you can see we already have the information on that, the name
server, that all the info stored in this server, why do we have this information?
So, if I go to the properties of this, the primary zone, and I go to zone transfer, you
can see that I've already, actually I am allowed the zone to be transferred to the secondary
server.
And if I go not to file, you can see, so that's all not to find the server, that this is
0, 2.
You can see it's actually green, you can see it's okay.
So, that's what the information has been transferred to the zone.
But without actually doing that transfer, the zone transfer, you can see you go naturally
received kind of a red check mark here, which means that the zone is not being transferred.
So, this is how you actually create a secondary zone.